<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sitecore on Sudeep&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/sitecore/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sitecore on Sudeep&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/categories/sitecore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore Launchpad apps and tools made easy with Bookmarklets</title>
      <link>/2016/12/sitecore-launchpad-apps-with-bookmarklets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 19:52:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/sitecore-launchpad-apps-with-bookmarklets/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you have worked with Sitecore for a while, in the version 6 or earlier days, you would remember that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of Launchpad back then. You would spend most of the time in the desktop mode because that&amp;rsquo;s how you access most of the apps, from the start menu. Or the desktop shortcuts, which I almost never used, and I doubt most people even knew of. The biggest problem with the desktop mode (apart from being a memory hog) was, and it still is, that you would lose the state of the opened windows if you refresh the browser. And as developers, that&amp;rsquo;s what we do most of the time right.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;div class=&#34;figure center&#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/sitecore-launchpad-bookmarklets-1-desktop-6.png&#34;  alt=&#34; Sitecore 6 Desktop&#34;&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt; Sitecore 6 Desktop&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 7.1 / 7.2, but really the version 8 and we have now a very stable and handy Launchpad. And as the name suggests, it is the launch pad for the commonly used sitecore applications, and also the new modern SPEAK apps. So you don&amp;rsquo;t have to rely much on the desktop mode now.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;div class=&#34;figure center&#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/sitecore-launchpad-bookmarklets-2-launchpad-8.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Sitecore 8 Launchpad&#34;&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Sitecore 8 Launchpad&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;However in saying that, now you need to come back to the Launchpad whenever you need to switch to a different app. This is an extra page load inbetween switching apps. This is still far from a painful experience but I would definitely prefer to cut this &amp;ldquo;middle&amp;rdquo; page out. I think It is the laziness in me (or my impatience?) that drives me to look for quicker ways to improvise such tedious workflows. And so the hunt began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-find&#34;&gt;The Find&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a chrome extension called &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/sitecore-developer-tool/cmbppbejihcnbngefandoljljdppnlda&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sitecore Developer Tool&lt;/a&gt; that gives you nice little shortcuts to most common pages/apps in Sitecore. Exactly what I wanted, this tool works with the sitecore url in the current browser tab and lets you quickly switch between admin pages, apps, databases and modes without having to go to the Launchpad or Desktop mode or type the url. Great!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bad&#34;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may not be a problem for you if you primarily use Chrome for Sitecore, but lately I have been using Firefox for everything Sitecore. So the biggest drawback for me now is this tool does not have a Firefox counterpart. And I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any other equivalent. So I had to come up with something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bookmarklets&#34;&gt;The Bookmarklets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easy solution was to write bookmarklets. To achieve a similar functionality, I created bookmarklets to most of the common sitecore apps that are accessible from the launchpad and also the admin pages and other tools. These bookmarklets are basically normal bookmarks with scripts to calculate the context site url, hence very light-weight and works with most popular browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bookmarklet is a bookmark stored in a web browser that contains JavaScript commands that add new features to the browser. Bookmarklets are unobtrusive JavaScripts stored as the URL of a bookmark in a web browser or as a hyperlink on a web page. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bookmarklet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read more here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple and light-weight&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;works on any sitecore url&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;works on most major browsers&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can be synced between different browsers and machines using tools like Xmarks Bookmark Sync&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily editable and extendable as they are just bookmarks&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



 
  
  
  
  
    
  
    
      
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure center&#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/sitecore-launchpad-bookmarklets-3-chrome.png&#34; title=&#34;Sitecore Launchpad Bookmarkets in Chrome&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:bookmarklets&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/sitecore-launchpad-bookmarklets-3-chrome.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Sitecore Launchpad Bookmarkets in Chrome&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Sitecore Launchpad Bookmarkets in Chrome&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;




 
  
  
  
  
    
  
    
      
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure center&#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/sitecore-launchpad-bookmarklets-4-firefox.png&#34; title=&#34;Sitecore Launchpad Bookmarkets in Firefox&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:bookmarklets&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/sitecore-launchpad-bookmarklets-4-firefox.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Sitecore Launchpad Bookmarkets in Firefox&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Sitecore Launchpad Bookmarkets in Firefox&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-install&#34;&gt;How to Install&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sud33p/f6431437247ce937eff2bd4abcad6d6e/raw/32e848108ecdda3ebb21ffbf8c82d047a3fb7770/Sitecore%2520Launchpad%2520Bookmarklets.html&#34; download=&#34;SitecoreLaunchpadBookmarklets.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; the bookmarks HTML file from the gist below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Import the HTML file into your browser via its bookmark manager.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will see a bookmarks folder called &lt;strong&gt;Sitecore Launchpad&lt;/strong&gt; being imported to the browser&amp;rsquo;s default import location. Feel free to move it where you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The HTML file to import&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sud33p/f6431437247ce937eff2bd4abcad6d6e/raw/32e848108ecdda3ebb21ffbf8c82d047a3fb7770/Sitecore%2520Launchpad%2520Bookmarklets.html&#34; download=&#34;SitecoreLaunchpadBookmarklets.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;//gist.github.com/sud33p/f6431437247ce937eff2bd4abcad6d6e.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDS cannot remove template and says it&#39;s in use.. but it isn&#39;t!!!</title>
      <link>/2016/10/tds-cannot-remove-says-its-in-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 20:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/tds-cannot-remove-says-its-in-use/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Have you seen this error before? You normally get this on the TDS sync window when TDS says the template is &lt;code&gt;Missing in Project&lt;/code&gt; and you will choose to &lt;code&gt;Remove from Sitecore&lt;/code&gt; but the error window says nah, can&amp;rsquo;t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-NONE&#34;&gt;An exception occurred while updating the sitecore item /sitecore/item/path/name.

The &amp;quot;name&amp;quot; template is in use.

Delete all the items that are based on this template.

Please see the output window for more details.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;



 
  
  
  
  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure &#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-1-sync-error.png&#34; title=&#34;TDS says the template is in use&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:tds&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-1-sync-error.png&#34;  alt=&#34;TDS says the template is in use&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;TDS says the template is in use&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;First of all, the word &amp;ldquo;occured&amp;rdquo; in the screenshot is incorrect, says &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/occured&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wiktionary&lt;/a&gt;. But nothing worse than getting this error when you are trying to do a sync on a long list of new/deleted/updated items/templates/whatever, presumably after isolating yourself on your solo &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; branch for a while.. Actually, the worst one has to be the one where TDS does not have a clue what to blame and just throws an exception. And then you have to scroll down the sync window to find the broken items and manually remove them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is equally bad because there isn&amp;rsquo;t any item that&amp;rsquo;s using the named template. You know there isn&amp;rsquo;t, but TDS says otherwise. So you have to investigate. &amp;ldquo;Links&amp;rdquo; button on the &amp;ldquo;Navigate&amp;rdquo; ribbon to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Content Editor &amp;gt; Navigate (ribbon) &amp;gt; Links&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;


 
  
  
  
  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure &#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-2-links-window.png&#34; title=&#34;Checking the Links referral&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:tds&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-2-links-window.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Checking the Links referral&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Checking the Links referral&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what? No content item is using it. The Links window shows a rendering, but it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t as it was updated to use something else, I swear. Let&amp;rsquo;s check further.&lt;/p&gt;



 
  
  
  
  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure &#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-3-links-rendering.png&#34; title=&#34;Checking the rendering datasource template&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:tds&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-3-links-rendering.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Checking the rendering datasource template&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Checking the rendering datasource template&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;




 
  
  
  
  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure &#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-4-links-branch-source.png&#34; title=&#34;Checking the branch item template&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:tds&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-4-links-branch-source.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Checking the branch item template&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Checking the branch item template&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So further investigation proves that the listed rendering is not using the template at all. What now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now obvious that the Links window is not reporting correctly. So definitely a problem with the Links database. Let&amp;rsquo;s go ahead an rebuild it, the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; database at a minimum as that&amp;rsquo;s our concern here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Control Panel &amp;gt; (Database) &amp;gt; Rebuild link databases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

 
  
  
  
  
    
      
    
  
    
      
    
  
    
  

 
  
  
  
  
    
  
    
      
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure left&#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-5-links-rebuild.png&#34; title=&#34;Rebuild Link Databases&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:tds&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-5-links-rebuild.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Rebuild Link Databases&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Rebuild Link Databases&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div style=&#34;clear:both;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now check back on the Links window, there is nothing referring to our template now.&lt;br /&gt;


 
  
  
  
  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure &#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-6-links-window-clean.png&#34; title=&#34;Checking the Links referral again&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:tds&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/tds-inuse-6-links-window-clean.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Checking the Links referral again&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Checking the Links referral again&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and re-sync TDS. It should be able to remove the template now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So looks like TDS goes through the same sitecore middle layer or uses it for its operations. So next time, if you get this error and you are pretty sure the template is not in use, just go ahead and try your luck by rebuilding the links database.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore and Symlinks (Symbolic Links)</title>
      <link>/2016/09/sitecore-and-symlinks-symbolic-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 01:02:07 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/09/sitecore-and-symlinks-symbolic-links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You must be wondering, what&amp;rsquo;s the relation here? There isn&amp;rsquo;t really, yet there could very well be one, if you want&amp;hellip; You are probably aware that there are lots of ways to structure a sitecore (VS) solution. I swear if I get a dollar for every time I see a new way of structuring sitecore projects, I would be 100 dollars richer (yea, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there are more than 100 ways). That&amp;rsquo;s still a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to the topic. Recently, one of the projects that I worked on had a slightly different approach of structuring projects/folders in the solution, mainly the Website publish folder where the web project publishes into. One of the very popular ways to arrange your sitecore project is to keep your sitecore website files separate from the codebase. This approach has a lot of benefits as opposed to developing directly on top of your IIS website folder. If you are not familiar with this development technique, I suggest you read Sean Kearney&amp;rsquo;s post &lt;a href=&#34;http://seankearney.com/post/Visual-Studio-Projects-and-Sitecore&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though this project followed the technique of separating the sitecore website files from the code project, the sitecore website folder was still kept inside the solution folder, the source controlled area. Gitignores were used to prevent the folder content from getting tracked. This meant that the placement of the other two folders that are part of the sitecore installation (Data and Databases), were left to the dev&amp;rsquo;s discretion. Below is an example of such a structure.&lt;/p&gt;



 
  
  
  
  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure &#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/sitecore-symlinks-diagram-1.png&#34; title=&#34;Sitecore install folder on left, Repo on the right&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:symlinks&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/sitecore-symlinks-diagram-1.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Sitecore install folder on left, Repo on the right&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Sitecore install folder on left, Repo on the right&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The sitecore install folder is on the left, which normally contains of &amp;lsquo;Data, Databases and Website&amp;rsquo; folders. The &amp;lsquo;Website&amp;rsquo; folder has been moved to the right here. This isn&amp;rsquo;t so bad per se, sitting at a relative location to the solution is a benefit. But if you are working on multiple projects or someone new joins the team, this can get confusing. I was not a big fan. Can we for once get best of both worlds?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;symlinks-to-the-rescue&#34;&gt;Symlinks to the rescue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Symlinks you can create a junction link on the sitecore install folder, pointing to the &amp;lsquo;Website&amp;rsquo; folder on the Repo. And it will make it look like the &amp;lsquo;Website&amp;rsquo; folder exists within the install folder with all its contents, even though it is just a reference to the actual &amp;lsquo;Website&amp;rsquo; folder within the repo. Think of it as an advanced shortcut, similar to the Windows shortcut link (.lnk) but with greater power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are Symlinks anyway?&lt;br /&gt;
Symlinks or Symbolic links, are basically advanced shortcuts. You can create symbolic links to individual files or folders, and then these will appear like they are stored in the folder with the symbolic link even though the symbolic link only points to their real location. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.howtogeek.com/howto/16226/complete-guide-to-symbolic-links-symlinks-on-windows-or-linux/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read more here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-command&#34;&gt;The command&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Syntax:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;MKLINK [[/D] | [/H] | [/J]] Link Target&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
        /D          Creates a directory symbolic link.  Default is a file symbolic link.&lt;br /&gt;
        /H          Creates a hard link instead of a symbolic link.&lt;br /&gt;
        /J          Creates a Directory Junction.&lt;br /&gt;
        Link        Specifies the new symbolic link name.&lt;br /&gt;
        Target      Specifies the path (relative or absolute) that the new link refers to.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our purpose, we need to create a directory junction &lt;code&gt;(/J)&lt;/code&gt; to link to the Website folder. So lets go ahead and do that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open command prompt (in Admin mode)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enter the command &lt;code&gt;mklink /J Link Target&lt;/code&gt;. In our case:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;D:\Dev\Sites\ClientA&amp;gt;mklink /J Website D:\Dev\Repos\ClientA\src\Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If successful, we will see the following output:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-default&#34;&gt;Junction created for Website &amp;lt;&amp;lt;===&amp;gt;&amp;gt; D:\Dev\Repos\ClientA\src\Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert info no-icon &#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
`MKLINK` is a built-in command line symlink tool in Windows Vista and above. If you are more of a GUI person, &lt;a href=&#34;http://schinagl.priv.at/nt/hardlinkshellext/linkshellextension.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Link Shell Extension&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent free tool for you. It also supports Windows XP.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should now have a symlink named &amp;lsquo;Website&amp;rsquo; created in the sitecore install folder which appears as a folder but is really pointing to the &amp;lsquo;Website&amp;rsquo; folder in the repo. You can identify by the little shortcut icon on it.&lt;/p&gt;



 
  
  
  
  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure &#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/sitecore-symlinks-diagram-2.png&#34; title=&#34;Directory junction created&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:symlinks&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/sitecore-symlinks-diagram-2.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Directory junction created&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Directory junction created&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and open it. You should see all of the same website content listed underneath.&lt;/p&gt;



 
  
  
  
  
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure &#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;/images/sitecore-symlinks-diagram-3.png&#34; title=&#34;Sitecore install folder on left, Repo on the right&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;group:symlinks&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;/images/sitecore-symlinks-diagram-3.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Sitecore install folder on left, Repo on the right&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Sitecore install folder on left, Repo on the right&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As a quick test, create a test file underneath either of the folder. You will see it appear immediately under the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All done. Now you can use this symlink reference as a real &amp;lsquo;Website&amp;rsquo; folder for anything you want, be it for IIS site path, TDS project or grunt/gulp tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert warning no-icon &#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
One thing to remember is, even though these symlinks are a reference to the original item, they do not inherit permissions. So if you are going to use it for say, an IIS site, make sure to set appropriate permissions on the symlink as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>