<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sitecore on Sudeep&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/sitecore/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sitecore on Sudeep&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 14:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sitecore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore&#39;s route keys &#39;scItemPath&#39; and &#39;scLanguage&#39; doesn&#39;t get processed when used with custom routes in MVC Areas (bug?)</title>
      <link>/2017/10/sitecore-route-keys-in-mvc-areas-does-not-get-processed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 14:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/sitecore-route-keys-in-mvc-areas-does-not-get-processed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded an instance from Sitecore 8.1 update 3 to 8.2 update 5 and cleaned up/refactored a lot of code, especially moved the initialization stuffs from the global.asax &lt;em&gt;Application_Start&lt;/em&gt; method into custom &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;initialize&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; pipelines. As part of the clean-up, I removed the &lt;code&gt;AreaRegistration.RegisterAllAreas()&lt;/code&gt; call as Sitecore now does it within the &lt;em&gt;InitializeRoutes&lt;/em&gt; pipeline:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore&#39;s site definition name cannot start with a number</title>
      <link>/2017/08/sitecore-site-definition-name-cannot-start-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 18:55:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/sitecore-site-definition-name-cannot-start-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I felt the need for this post because first of all, this is most likely a rare scenario where you will need to name a site definition starting with a number. And when you do, the error you get will baffle you as it is in no way directly related to the change you&amp;rsquo;ve made. Let me explain!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore Launchpad apps and tools made easy with Bookmarklets</title>
      <link>/2016/12/sitecore-launchpad-apps-with-bookmarklets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 19:52:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/sitecore-launchpad-apps-with-bookmarklets/</guid>
      <description>If you have worked with Sitecore for a while, in the version 6 or earlier days, you would remember that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of Launchpad back then. You would spend most of the time in the desktop mode because that&amp;rsquo;s how you access most of the apps, from the start menu. Or the desktop shortcuts, which I almost never used, and I doubt most people even knew of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDS cannot remove template and says it&#39;s in use.. but it isn&#39;t!!!</title>
      <link>/2016/10/tds-cannot-remove-says-its-in-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 20:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/tds-cannot-remove-says-its-in-use/</guid>
      <description>Have you seen this error before? You normally get this on the TDS sync window when TDS says the template is Missing in Project and you will choose to Remove from Sitecore but the error window says nah, can&amp;rsquo;t do it.
An exception occurred while updating the sitecore item /sitecore/item/path/name. The &amp;quot;name&amp;quot; template is in use. Delete all the items that are based on this template. Please see the output window for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore and Symlinks (Symbolic Links)</title>
      <link>/2016/09/sitecore-and-symlinks-symbolic-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 01:02:07 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/09/sitecore-and-symlinks-symbolic-links/</guid>
      <description>You must be wondering, what&amp;rsquo;s the relation here? There isn&amp;rsquo;t really, yet there could very well be one, if you want&amp;hellip; You are probably aware that there are lots of ways to structure a sitecore (VS) solution. I swear if I get a dollar for every time I see a new way of structuring sitecore projects, I would be 100 dollars richer (yea, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there are more than 100 ways).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>